Guide to the Carl Van Vechten Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1907-1971; Series I; 79.8; 183 boxes
  - A-Z Correspondence
    - Laing, Hugh
      - 1930–1945 (Box 72, Folder 1017-1018)
        Includes letter from Andrew Westervelt to CVV (1945)
      - 1946-1967, undated (Box 73, Folder 1019-1020)
        Includes photograph of Laing and Annabelle Lyon in performance, with letter from Andrew C. Westervelt to CVV (1946)
    - Lamson, Roy, 1948–1949 (Box 73, Folder 1021)
    - Lane, Leo, 1934 (Box 73, Folder 1022)
    - Langner, Lawrence, 1925–1963 (Box 73, Folder 1023-1024)
      Includes letters and notes signed by Langner's wife, Armina Marshall, and program from Langner's memorial tribute
    - Langner, Philip, 1936–1970 (Box 73, Folder 1025-1026)
      Includes letters and notes signed by Langner's wife, Marilyn Clark Langner, and daughters Lola Langner and Eve Langner
    - Larsen, Ethel L., 1953–1961 (Box 73, Folder 1027)
    - Larsson, Raymond Ellsworth, 1930-[196?] (Box 73, Folder 1028-1029)
      Includes poems written by Larsson for Muriel Draper, Mabel Dodge Luhan, Beatrice Locher, Gertrude Stein, CVV, and FM
    - Lasky, Bessie Mona, 1930–1934 (Box 73, Folder 1030)
    - Laughlin, James, 1940; 1949; undated (Box 73, Folder 1031)
      Includes letter from Laughlin to Alice B. Toklas (1949); letter from Laughlin to Bennet Cerf (undated)
    - Laurence, Paula, 1953–1958 (Box 73, Folder 1032)
    - Lawrence, Jerome, 1958-1965, undated (Box 73, Folder 1033-1034)
      Includes typescript mimeograph commencement address at Ohio State University by Lawrence, enclosed with letter from Lawrence to CVV (1963)
      See also: Weissberger, L. Arnold
    - Lawrence, Neil, 1937–1940 (Box 74, Folder 1035)
    - Le Gallienne, Eva, 1953 May 15 (Box 74, Folder 1036)
    - Lederman, Minna, 1952–1962 (Box 74, Folder 1037)
    - Lee, Alyne Dumas, 1953-1954, undated (Box 74, Folder 1038)
    - Lee, Auriol, 1934; 1941 (Box 74, Folder 1039)
    - Lee, Robert E., 1961–1964 (Box 74, Folder 1040)
    - Lehman, B. H. (Benjamin Harrison), 1937–1942 (Box 74, Folder 1041)
      Includes letters signed by Lehman as Peter Lehman
    - Lehman, Herbert H. (Herbert Henry), 1957–1958 (Box 74, Folder 1042)
    - Leigh-Emmerich Lecture Bureaus, Inc., 1924–1928 (Box 74, Folder 1043)
      Includes letters signed by W. Colston Leigh and F. J. Emmerich
    - Lerman, Leo, 1948-1970, undated (Box 74, Folder 1044-1045)
      Includes notes signed by Lerman's companion, Gray Foy
    - Lerner, Sam, 1944 (Box 74, Folder 1046)
      Includes three typescript poems by Lerner, enclosed with letter to CVV
    - Leslie, Anita, 1954 September 25 (Box 74, Folder 1047)
    - Levee Press, 1947–1948 (Box 74, Folder 1048)
    - Levere, Lee, 1957-1970, undated (Box 74, Folder 1049-1050)
      Includes photograph of Levere with note to FM on verso (undated)
    - Levy, Marvin David, 1960-1967, undated (Box 74, Folder 1051-1054)
    - Lewis, Robert, 1939–1948 (Box 75, Folder 1055)
    - Lewis, Sinclair, 1923–1938 (Box 75, Folder 1056)
    - Lewis, W. S. (Wilmarth Sheldon), 1967 September 15 (Box 75, Folder 1057)
    - Lewis, William E., 1916–1918 (Box 75, Folder 1058)
    - Leyendecker [Frank?], 1964 March 23 (Box 75, Folder 1059)
    - Library of Congress, 1949–1950 (Box 75, Folder 1060)
      Consists of letters from Paul Vanderbilt of the Prints and Photographs Division
    - Lieberson, Goddard, 1932–1964 (Box 75, Folder 1061)
      Includes typescript poems by Lieberson, enclosed with letter from Lieberson to CVV (1934)
    - Liebert, Herman W., 1950-1960, undated (Box 75, Folder 1062)
      Includes notes signed by Liebert's wife, Laura Liebert
    - Liebler, T. A., 1916 (Box 75, Folder 1063)
    - Liebowitz, David, 1922–1923 (Box 75, Folder 1064)
    - Light, Karl M., 1948-1950, undated (Box 75, Folder 1065-1066)
      Includes poems by Light, enclosed with letters to CVV (1949, 1950)
    - Lin, Hong, 1937-1969, undated (Box 75, Folder 1067-1069)
      Includes notes from Hong and Yutang Lin's daughters, Adet Lin and Anor (Tai-yi) Lin; third-party letters to CVV from The John Day Company, Inc. Publishers (1937-1940); typescript introduction, foreword, and table of contents of the cookbook The Chinese Flavor, by Yutang and Hong Lin, enclosed with letter to CVV (1955)
    - Lin, Yutang, 1936-1970, undated (Box 75, Folder 1070-1071)
      Includes letters and cards signed by Yutang and Hong Lin
    - Lineberry, Duane V.V., 1961–1964 (Box 76, Folder 1072)
    - Lion, Leon M., 1935-1937, undated (Box 76, Folder 1073)
    - Liscomb, Harry F., 1925–1930 (Box 76, Folder 1074)
    - Literary Review, 1921 (Box 76, Folder 1075)
    - Liveright, Horace, 1923-1933, undated (Box 76, Folder 1076)
      Includes letter from Edward P. Smith to Liveright and carbon copy of Liveright's response, enclosed with letter to FM (1925)
    - Living Theatre
      See: Beck, Julian
    - Locher, Robert E., 1937-1955, undated (Box 76, Folder 1077)
    - Empty folder (Box 76, Folder 1078)
    - Loos, Anita, 1926–1964 (Box 76, Folder 1079)
    - Lovett, Robert Morss, 1923–1950 (Box 76, Folder 1080)
      Includes galley proof of Lovett's review of Love Days by Henrie Waste published in The New Republic, enclosed with letter from Lovett to CVV (1923)
    - Lowndes, Norman, 1946 September 13 (Box 76, Folder 1081)
    - Loy, Mina, 1914-1959, undated (Box 76, Folder 1082-1083)
    - Luce, Clare Boothe, 1938–1958 (Box 76, Folder 1084)
    - Lucioni, Luigi, 1939-1952, undated (Box 76, Folder 1085)
    - Lueder, Florence Wickham, 1931; 1935 (Box 76, Folder 1086)
      Includes letter fragments from Paul Kester enclosed with Lueder's letters to CVV (1931)
    - Lueders, Edward
      Includes autograph and typescript letters from CVV to Lueders, and carbon copies of Lueder's letters to CVV
      Letters to Lueders from CVV, and Lueders's copies of letters to CVV, gift of Edward Lueders, 1981
      - 1950–1958 (Box 76, Folder 1087-1090)
        Includes photographs of Lueders with his son Kurt Lueders, enclosed with letters from Lueders to CVV (1951); photocopies of letters from Lueders to his wife, Judy Lueders (1951); photographic postcard of Edward Lueders (circa 1951); typed copy of letter from Lueders to Alfred A. Knopf, enclosed with Lueders' letter to CVV (1952); typed transcript, carbon copy, of letter from Mabel Dodge Luhan to Lueders (1955)
      - 1959–1971 (Box 77, Folder 1091-1096)
        Includes photographic postcard of CVV with Charles S. Johnson at Fisk University in 1955, with note from CVV to Lueders on verso (1959); typed letters, carbon copies, from Lueders to Bruce Kellner (1962); "Miami Beach," poem, typescript, by Lueders, enclosed with letter from Lueders to CVV (1962); typed letter, carbon copy, from Lueders to Saul Mauriber (1965)
    - Luhan, Mabel Dodge
      See also: Photoduplicated letters from Luhan to CVV in Box 176
      - 1913–1927 (Box 77, Folder 1097-1101)
        Includes photograph of Luhan on a horse, enclosed with letter from Luhan to CVV (1920); printed appeals and protest of artists and writers against the Bursum Indian Bill, enclosed with letter from Luhan to CVV (1922); poems by John Reed, manuscript copies, enclosed with letter from Luhan to CVV (1924)
      - El Paso Morning Times clipping, 1913 December 20 (Box 182 (Oversize), Folder 2331)
        Front page of the El Paso Morning Times, previously enclosed with letter from Luhan to CVV postmarked 1913 December 20
      - 1928–1952 (Box 78, Folder 1102-1109)
        Includes letter from Blanche Knopf's secretary to CVV with copy of letter from Luhan to Blanche Knopf enclosed (1930); letter from Alfred A. Knopf to Luhan, enclosed with letter from Luhan to CVV (1931); photograph of John Evans enclosed with note from Luhan to CVV (1951); typed carbon copy of codicil to Luhan's will, enclosed with letter from Luhan to CVV (1951)
      - El Creeps clipping, 1951 August (Box 182 (Oversize), Folder 2332)
        Front page of the 1951 August 9 issue of El Creeps, a humor newspaper published in Taos, New Mexico, with manuscript note by Luhan to CVV written on upper left hand corner, with envelope postmarked 1951 August 13
      - 1953-1962, undated (Box 79, Folder 1110-1111)
        Includes photograph of Luhan made at the Villa Curonia in Florence, Italy, with notes by Luhan and CVV on verso (undated); unsent postcard with note from CVV to Luhan (undated)
      - The New Mexican clipping, 1953 (Box 182 (Oversize), Folder 2333)
        Clipping from an undated issue of The New Mexican, previously enclosed with letter dated 1953 February 26 from Luhan to CVV
    - Lumet, Sidney, 1939–1961 (Box 79, Folder 1112)
    - Lunt, Alfred, 1923-1968, undated (Box 79, Folder 1113)
      Includes letters from Lunt's wife, Lynn Fontanne; cancelled check to Lynn Fontanne from CVV (1958)
    - Lutz, Mark
      Includes letters from Lutz's mother, Mary E. Lutz to CVV; autograph and typescript letters from CVV to Lutz
      CVV letters to Lutz, gift of William Jepson, 1969
      - 1932–1949 (Box 79, Folder 1114-1120)
        Includes typescript biographical notes on James A. Bland and Richmond Barthé (circa 1939)
      - 1950 June–1953 July (Box 80, Folder 1121-1128)
        Includes photograph of a chair, enclosed with letter from Lutz to CVV (1953)
      - 1954 September–1956 June (Box 81, Folder 1129-1136)
        Includes autograph letter, signed, from Dorothy Peterson to Lutz, enclosed with letter from Lutz to CVV (1955); photograph of two dogs enclosed with letter from Lutz to CVV (1956)
      - 1956 July–1957 June (Box 82, Folder 1137-1144)
      - 1957 July–1958 June (Box 83, Folder 1145-1153)
        Includes photograph of Edward Lueder, enclosed with letter from Lutz to CVV (1957)
      - 1958 July–1959 August (Box 84, Folder 1154-1162)
        Includes photograph of two dogs, enclosed with letter from Lutz to CVV (1959)
      - 1959 September–1960 September (Box 85, Folder 1163-1171)
        Includes copy of a General Memorandum from Robert M. Jones of the Philco company with photograph of Percy LaBohne, enclosed with letter from Lutz to CVV (1959)
      - 1960 October–1961 December (Box 86, Folder 1172-1179)
        Includes letter from Stella Moore of the Philadelphia Art Alliance, and letter from Sadie E. Engelborg to Lutz, enclosed with letter from Lutz to CVV (1961)
      - 1962 January–1963 April (Box 87, Folder 1180-1188)
        Includes letters from William Jepson to CVV (1962); letter from Donald Angus to Lutz, enclosed with letter from Lutz to CVV (1963)
      - 1963 May–1964 December (Box 88, Folder 1189-1196)
      - 1965-1967, undated (Box 89, Folder 1197-1200)
        Includes typed transcript of letter from the Philadelphia Museum of Art to Lutz, enclosed with letter from Lutz to FM (1965)
    - Lyle, Alice, 1928–1932 (Box 89, Folder 1201)
      Includes notes signed as Jessie P. Lyle and Mrs. Henry Hamilton Moore Lyle
    - Lynes, George Platt, 1926; 1932 (Box 89, Folder 1202)
      Includes untitled poem, typescript, signed with initials "gpl," enclosed with letter from Lynes to CVV (1926)
    - "M" General, 1906-1964, undated (Box 90, Folder 1203-1210)
    - Mabry, Iris, 1948–1954 (Box 90, Folder 1211)
    - Mabry, Thomas, 1933–1954 (Box 90, Folder 1212)
    - MacCallum, Russell, 1958–1963 (Box 91, Folder 1213)
      Includes photographs of MacCallum family members, enclosed with letters from MacCallum to CVV (1958, 1960)
    - MacFadyen, Virginia, 1922 May 22 (Box 91, Folder 1214)
      Poem written for FM, accompanied by note
    - Machen, Arthur, 1922-1959, undated (Box 91, Folder 1215)
      Includes typed letter, carbon copy, from CVV to Machen (1922); letters from the Arthur Machen Society
    - MacIver, Hughie, 1953–1965 (Box 91, Folder 1216)
    - MacIver, Irene, 1931-1971, undated (Box 91, Folder 1217-1220)
    - MacKellar, Helen, 1922 April 24 (Box 91, Folder 1221)
    - Macmillan Company, 1916; 1964 (Box 91, Folder 1222)
    - Macpherson, Kenneth, 1927–1943 (Box 91, Folder 1223)
    - Madden, Clarence L., 1920-1934, undated (Box 91, Folder 1224)
      Includes typed letters, carbon copies, from Madden to "Mr. Pollock," and Pollock's response (1934); photograph of Madden's cat (undated)
    - Madsen, Elmer D., 1949-1951, undated (Box 91, Folder 1225)
    - Magill, Frank N., 1948–1950 (Box 92, Folder 1226)
    - Mailer, Norman, 1948 (Box 92, Folder 1227)
      Typed letter, signed, from Norman Mailer, accompanied by printed Civil Rights Congress anti-Jim Crow pledge, to CVV, with CVV's typed carbon copy response
    - Mainbocher, 1941-1965, undated (Box 92, Folder 1228)
    - Malina, Judith
    - Maloney, Tom, 1936–1937 (Box 92, Folder 1229)
      Includes letters signed by Evelyn F. Lamorey
    - Man Ray, 1930–1934 (Box 92, Folder 1230)
    - Mandelstam, Abraham, 1944–1964 (Box 92, Folder 1231)
    - Mansfield, Richard Gibbs, 1916 (Box 92, Folder 1232)
    - Marble-Pollock, Anna
      Includes CVV's letters, notes and postcards (including CVV photographic postcards) to Marble-Pollock
      CVV's letters to Anna Marble-Pollock gift of Helen Channing Pollock through CVV, 1947
      - 1915–1936 (Box 92, Folder 1233-1237)
      - 1937–1939 (Box 93, Folder 1238-1244)
        Includes letter from William H. Forsyth, Jr. of the Metropolitan Museum of Art to Marble-Pollock, with autograph note from M-P to CVV (1936); two letters from Mary Marble to CVV (1938)
      - 1940–1943 (Box 94, Folder 1245-1252)
        Includes letter from Charles Hanson Towne to Marble-Pollock, enclosed with letter from M-P to CVV (1940); letter from Edith Thompson to M-P with typed note from M-P to CVV (1940); fragment of newspaper clipping glued to page with limerick about CVV by M-P typed below (1940); letter from Alison Skipworth to M-P, enclosed with letter from M-P to CVV (1941); note from Fulton Oursler to M-P (1941); letters from Audi H. D'Avi and Ann Coleman to M-P with envelope addressed to CVV (1942)
      - 1944 January–1944 July (Box 95, Folder 1253-1259)
        Includes letter from Edward L. Smith to M-P, enclosed with letter from M-P to CVV (1944); two notes from Fulton Oursler to M-P, enclosed with notes from M-P to CVV (1944); bookplate for the Gershwin Collection at Fisk University Library enclosed with letter from CVV to M-P (1944); postcard from Ann Coleman to M-P with envelope addressed to CVV (1944); letter from the American Museum of Natural History, New York, to M-P, enclosed with letter from M-P to CVV (1944); V-Mail from John Bianco to M-P, enclosed with letter from M-P to CVV (1944)
      - 1944 August–1945 March (Box 96, Folder 1260-1267)
        Includes notes from Margaret Bower, John Dunn and Mary Marble, Edith [Thompson?], and Mary Davenport Seymour to M-P, enclosed with letters from M-P to CVV (1944); "Heresy," typescript poem, carbon copy, by M-P, enclosed with letter from M-P to CVV (1944); "While the BBC Played Elgar," typescript poem, mimeograph copy, by Gerard Willem van Loon, enclosed with letter from M-P to CVV (1944)
      - 1945 April–1945 October (Box 97, Folder 1268-1276)
        Includes photographic postcard of Fania Marinoff, Rollo Peters, and Dorothy Gish in The Bride the Sun Shines On, with note from CVV to M-P (1945); letters from Ann Coleman, Fulton Oursler, Leonard Briley, Leicester Holland, Giovanni [Bianco?], Elizabeth Cooper to M-P (1945); letter from P-M's daughter Helen Pollock to CVV (1945)
      - 1945 November–1946 March (Box 98, Folder 1277-1286)
        Includes letters from Marion Boyd, Giovanni Bianco, Grace Oursler, Citizens Christmas Cheer Committee, Inc., Donald Boyd, Annette Davison to M-P, enclosed with letters to CVV (1945); letter from Mildred Webster to FM, enclosed with CVV letter to M-P( 1945); photographic postcard of Giovanni Bianco by CVV, enclosed with letter from CVV to M-P (1945); letter from Llewellyn R. Johnston to CVV, enclosed with letter from CVV to P-M (1946); photographic postcard of CVV in 1888, enclosed with letter to P-M (1946); letters from Mark Lutz to M-P (1946)
    - March, Florence, 1958 March 10 (Box 98, Folder 1287)
    - Marchant, Peter, 1951–1956 (Box 98, Folder 1288)
      Includes first issue of Manuscript Lab, the Writer's Workshop Magazine, containing a short story by Marchant with inscription to CVV (1956)
    - Marinoff, David, 1959-1970, undated (Box 99, Folder 1289)
      Includes letters from David Marinoff's wife Rosemary Marinoff; dust jacket for West of the Wind by David Marinoff (1969)
    - Marinoff, Fania
      - Correspondence with CVV, 1914-1963, undated (Box 99, Folder 1290-1291)
        Includes birthday verses written by FM to CVV (1948, 1951); photographic postcard of FM by CVV with note on verso (undated)
      - Greeting cards
        Commercial and hand-made birthday, anniversary, Valentine's Day, and other holiday cards exchanged between CVV and FM
        - FM to CVV, 1934-1964, undated (Box 179, Folder 2289-2293)
        - Framed Christmas card from FM to CVV, 1961 (Box 326)
        - CVV to FM
          - 1921–1949 (Box 179, Folder 2294-2295)
          - 1950-1964, undated (Box 180, Folder 2296-2299)
      - Condolence notes and telegrams to FM, 1964–1965 (Box 99, Folder 1292)
      - Fan letters to FM, 1916-1970, undated (Box 99, Folder 1293-1294)
        Includes congratulatory telegrams to FM from unidentified correspondents
    - Marinoff, Jacob, 1928-1966, undated (Box 99, Folder 1295-1296)
      Includes letter from Mrs. C. D. Spivak to Jacob Marinoff (1922); letters signed by Jacob Marinoff's wife, Esther Marinoff; birthday and anniversary verses and acrostics written by Marinoff; letter from Robert Moses of the Long Island State Park Commission to Marinoff (1931); letter from Art Young to Marinoff (1931); letter from CVV to Marinoff (1932); two certificates awarded to Jacob Marinoff by the National Committee for Labor Israel (1953 and undated)
    - Marinoff, Louis, 1959–1961 (Box 99, Folder 1297)
      Includes copy of Louis Marinoff's will, and letters from his attorney, Morris Rutland, regarding his estate
    - Marinoff, Nathan, 1939–1971 (Box 99, Folder 1298)
      Includes letters from Nathan Marinoff's wife, Esther Marinoff
    - Marinoff, Oscar, 1954–1970 (Box 99, Folder 1299)
      Includes letters from Oscar Marinoff's wife, Kate Marinoff; photograph of Marinoff family members enclosed with letter from Oscar and Kate Marinoff (1964)
    - Marinoff family members, 1902-1964, undated (Box 99, Folder 1300)
      Includes letters and notes from Fania Marinoff's father, Mayer Marinoff, and various nieces and nephews; photographs of family members, enclosed with letter from Hyman Marinoff to FM (1954)
    - Markova, Alicia, Dame, 1941-1964, undated (Box 100, Folder 1301-1307)
      Includes photograph of Markova with Harry Casey, enclosed with letter from Markova to CVV (1943); letter from Robert J. Vernon, Jr. to CVV (1946); letter from Markova's mother, Eileen Marks, to CVV (1947); letter from Leo G. Carroll and Mrs. Percy Moore to CVV (1949); letters from Markova's sister, Doris Barry, to CVV (1950, 1958)
    - Marshall, Armina, 1926-1971, undated (Box 100, Folder 1308-1310)
      Includes postcard from CVV to Marshall (1948); letter from Jane Weeks Martin to FM (1960); letters from Annie Kenny, the Langner's cook (1960, 1962); "Ode to Armina," by FM, typescript original and two carbon copies (undated)
      See also: Langner, Lawrence
    - Martin, John, 1941–1965 (Box 101, Folder 1311)
    - Martin, Lynn C., 1956–1964 (Box 101, Folder 1312)
    - Martin, Mary, 1945–1963 (Box 101, Folder 1313)
      Includes letters from Martin's husband, Richard Halliday
    - Martinson, Joseph B., 1938-1954, undated (Box 101, Folder 1314-1315)
      Includes letters from Martinson's wife, Florence Martinson (1944-1945)
    - Marvel, Henry R., undated (Box 101, Folder 1316)
    - Massary, Fritzi, 1941–1964 (Box 101, Folder 1317)
    - Massee, Jordan, 1958 (Box 101, Folder 1318)
    - Massey, Dorothy, 1958 October 16 (Box 101, Folder 1319)
    - Matisse, Pierre, 1933–1937 (Box 101, Folder 1320)
    - Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), 1928-1937, undated (Box 101, Folder 1321)
      Includes one letter from Maugham to CVV (1928); letters from Maugham's companion Frederick Gerald Haxton
    - Mauriber, Saul, 1948-1964, undated (Box 101, Folder 1322-1323)
      Includes cabinet photograph of the 1900 Paris Exposition sent as postcard from Mauriber to CVV (1952)
    - Mauriber, Sidney, 1958-1964, undated (Box 101, Folder 1324)
      Includes notes signed by Mauriber and his wife Dorothy Mauriber; photograph of Felicia Carla Mauriber enclosed with note from Mauriber to CVV (1958)
    - Maurois, André, 1930-1950, undated (Box 101, Folder 1325)
    - McBride, Henry, 1929–1958 (Box 101, Folder 1326-1327)
    - McCullers, Carson, 1959–1960 (Box 101, Folder 1328)
      Includes note from Mary E. Mercer to CVV (1959); letter from James F. Mathias, John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation, to CVV (1960)
    - McCurdy, Richard L., 1953–1954 (Box 101, Folder 1329)
    - McDonald, Paul
      See: Padgette, Paul
    - McKay, Almenia
      See: Williams, Almenia
    - McPhee, Colin, 1930-1944, undated (Box 102, Folder 1330)
    - Meltzer, Milton, 1967 November 20 (Box 102, Folder 1331)
    - Mencken, H.L. (Henry Louis), 1911-1959, undated (Box 102, Folder 1332-1337)
      Includes note from Percival Pollard to Mencken (1911); letter from Gladys Baker to CVV, enclosed with letter of introduction for Baker by Mencken to CVV (1929); letter from Alan Devoe to CVV with autograph note from CVV to Mencken (1930); letters from Mencken's wife Sara Mencken to CVV (1932-1934); letters from Edgar Kemler to CVV (1949); letter from August Mencken to CVV (1950); letters from Guy J. Forgue to CVV (1959); letter from Betty Adler to CVV, accompanied by Summer 1963, No. 6 issue of Menckeniana, published by the Enoch Pratt Free Library, Baltimore (1963)
      See also: Photoduplicated letters from Mencken to CVV in Box 176
    - Mendel, Arthur, 1944 (Box 102, Folder 1338)
    - Merande, Doro, [1948] (Box 102, Folder 1339)
    - Merivale, Philip, 1921 (Box 102, Folder 1340)
    - Merrick, Leonore, 1957; undated (Box 102, Folder 1341)
    - Metcalf, Addison M.
      - 1951–1956 (Box 102, Folder 1342-1344)
        Includes "'Rose is a Rose is a Rose is a Rose,' a Portrait," autograph manuscript poem by Metcalf, inscribed to CVV (1953); "When This You Read Remember Me," typescript poem, signed, by Metcalf (1954); Absolutely Bob Brown; or, Bobbed Brown, by Gertrude Stein, printed by Banyon Press, inscribed to CVV (1955)
      - 1957-1964, undated (Box 103, Folder 1345-1348)
        Includes sketch and printed copy of a bookplate design for Metcalf collection of Gertrude Steiniana, enclosed with letters from Metcalf to CVV (1958)
    - Metcalf, Henrietta A.
      - 1953–1960 (Box 103, Folder 1349-1352)
        Includes photographs of Lady Bird Cleveland, enclosed with notes from Metcalf to CVV (1953, 1960); photographs of Metcalf, cats and dogs enclosed with notes from Metcalf to CVV (1955, 1959, 1960); photograph of Patricia Cleveland, enclosed with note from Metcalf to CVV (1960)
      - 1961-1964, undated (Box 104, Folder 1353)
        Includes photograph of Michael Metcalf Harris, enclosed with letter from Metcalf to CVV (1962)
    - Metcalfe, James Stetson, 1916 May 19 (Box 104, Folder 1354)
      Letter to FM with printed copy of Metcalfe's play, Children of the Bard, inscribed to FM
    - Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1947; 1970; undated (Box 104, Folder 1355)
    - Metropolitan Opera (New York, N.Y.), 1955–1966 (Box 104, Folder 1356)
      Includes personal notes from Francis Robinson; third-party letters from Charles Brokow and Father Victor, P.F. M. (1956)
    - Metropolitan Opera Guild, 1946–1965 (Box 104, Folder 1357)
    - Meyerowitz, Jan, 1948–1950 (Box 104, Folder 1358)